17 Shannon Crescent, Watsonia, Victoria, Australia

□ (+61) 4 00 11 88 07 | Image: Image

"In God we trust, for everyone else, bring data."

Summary_

I am a medical doctor, completing a PhD in epidemiology and biostatistics with 7 years of clinical experience and 10 years of research experience, including supervising and leading research groups. I have experience in a wide range of clinical environments, and have managed small emergency departments as the senior medical officer.

I speak english and french fluently, am a citizen of the USA and Belgium (EU), and am a permanent resident of Australia. My areas of interest includes traditional predictive analytics, clinical trials design, machine learning and artificial intellegence in medicine.

Work Experience

Peter MacCallum Cancer Center

Melbourne, Austrlaia

PAIN FELLOW

August 2018 - PRESENT

- Led a inpatient care team comprised of nurses and junior doctors
- Created and guided research projects
- · Saw patients in an outpatient setting

General Practitioner /ED Career Medical Officer

Foster, Vic & Moruya/Bega NSW

February 2016 - Apr. 2016

COUNTRY GENERAL PRACTICE + ED LOCUM ROLES

- Lead (sole) Doctor in a Rural Emergency Department responsible for a 30 bed hospital
- · Managed patients as an independant practitioner

John Hunter Hospital& Peninsula Health

MEDICAL REGISTRAR

- · Learnt to manage patients as a senior doctor.
- Managed and Led Emergency Response Teams in a Tertiary Level Hospital
- Taught and supervised junior staff members

Newcastle, NSW & Frankston, VIC Jan. 2013 - Feb. 2016

Frankston, Austrlia

INTERNSHIP

February 2012 - 2013

• First year of clinical medicine experience as a junior doctor in Australia

Geneva University Hospital

• First Year Neurosurgery Trainee

NEUROSURGERY REGISTRAR

Peninsula Health

Geneva, Switzerland

- · Worked using French as primary medical language
- · Identified and managed neurosurgical emergencies

January 2011 - January 2012

Presentations

Australasian Epidemiology Association Annual Scientific Meeting

Freemantle, Perth

NATIONAL CONGRESS, METHODS SECTION

September 2018

 Brain cancers after CT scans: Using the 95th percentile of the pre-diagnostic symptomatic interval (PSI) to inform the choice of exclusion periods

Peter MacCallum Surgery and Anesthetic Research Day

Melbourne, Victoria

INTERDEPARTMENTAL PRESENTATION

December 2018

- Effect of CT scan Radiation on the Incidence of Brain Cancers
- · Effect of Day 1 Pain scores on length of stay

Education

University of Melbourne, School of Population and Global Health

Melbourne, Australia

PhD in Statistics and Epidemiology

March 2014 - Exp. March. 2020

Effect of CT scan Radiation on the Incidence of Brain Cancer

NICOLAS R. SMOLL · RÉSUMÉ **DECEMBER 18, 2018**

Monash University

Melbourne, Australia

BACHELOR OF MEDICINE /BACHELOR OF SURGERY

February 2007 - December 2011

· Completed medical school with 2 sole authored publications

Royal Melbourne Institue of Technology

MASTER OF SCIENCE

• Thesis: Outcomes Measurement in Tension-type and Cervicogenic Headache

Royal Melbourne Institue of Technology

BACHELOR OF APPLIED SCIENCE

· Paid tutoring in anatomy and neuroanatomy

Melbourne, Australia

February 2006 - December 2007

Melbourne, Australia

February 2002 - December 2005

Software Competency

Statistical Software Suites

OVER 1000 LINES OF CODE - SEE MY GITHUB FOR CODE EXAMPLES

- Stata 10 years experience, over 100 complete statistical analyses performed
- R use on big data situations
- Python Machine learning and AI libraries such as Scikit-Learn / TensorFlow / Keras

Software Systems

SEE MY GITHUB FOR CODE EXAMPLES

- MFX- Professional document typesetting system for documents/reports, presentations and graphic design.
- Python Website design. Used for building machine learning driven web apps for clinical usage.
- HTML Website front-end design
- SQL Competent in querying and managing SQL driven databases. Office Apps competent in microsoft, google, and other open office software suites

Research

Selected Publications

TOTAL OF 70+ PUBLICATIONS, H-INDEX 18, I-INDEX 36

- Smoll NR. Relative survival of childhood and adult medulloblastomas and primitive neuroectodermal tumors (PNETs). Cancer. 2012;118(5):1313-1322
- Sarrafzadeh A, **Smoll NR.**, Schaller K. Guided (VENTRI-GUIDE) versus freehand ventriculostomy: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2014;15(1):478.
- Stienen MN, **Smoll NR.**, Joswig H, et al. Validation of the baseline severity stratification of objective functional impairment in lumbar degenerative disc disease. J Neurosurg Spine. 2017;26(5)
- Gautschi OP, Stienen MN, Corniola M V., **Smoll NR.** et al. Assessment of the Minimum Clinically Important Difference in the Timed Up and Go Test After Surgery for Lumbar Degenerative Disc Disease. Neurosurgery. June 2016:1
- Smoll NR. Variations of the piriformis and sciatic nerve with clinical consequence: A review. Clin Anat New York NY. 2010;23(1):8-17. doi:10.1002/ca.20893.